저리 비켜!
Out of the way!
비키란 말이야!
여긴 디셔 형사다
용의자를 추격하고 있다
This is Disher.
We're in pursuit on foot.
찰스턴 가 서쪽이다
용의자는 무장한 위험인물이다
West on Charleston.
Suspect is armed and dangerous.
- 다 비켜!
- 반복한다. 무장한 위험인물이다
- Out of the way!
- Repeat, armed and dangerous.
베이지 색 상의에
자주색 셔츠를 입고 있다
He's wearing a beige suit
and a purple shirt.
자주색인 것 같지만
라벤더 색이나 담황색일 수도 있다
I think it's purple. It might be lavender
or mauve, I'm not sure.
랜디, 셔츠 색은 대충 말해도 돼!
Randy, nobody cares about the shirt!
지원을 요청한다!
지원이 필요하다!
Request backup.
We need backup!
꼼짝 마!
여잘 놔줘!
Freeze! Freeze!
Let the girl go!
움직이지 마!
총 내려놔!
Don't move!
Put the gun down!
- 여자를 놔줘, 에스코바
- 농담 아니야! 여잘 죽일 거야!
- Let the girl go, Escobar.
- I swear to god, I'll kill her!
- 모두 진정하세요!
- 여자를 놔줘!
- Everybody relax. Relax!
- Let the girl go!
- 당장 총을 내려놔!
- 알았다
- You put the gun down now!
- Okay.
내려놔
총 내려놔
Put it down.
알았어
Okay.
그 사람이야. 미겔 에스코바
뉴스에 나온 걸 봤어
That's him. That's Miguel Escobar.
Which I saw him on the news.
- 저 사람 1급 현상범이던데!
- 네, 이제는 아니죠
- He's the number 1 most wanted man!
- Yeah, not any more.
- 부탁 하나 들어주시겠소, 경감?
- 입 닥쳐!
- Would you do me a favor, captain?
- Shut up!
내 약혼녀한테 전화해서
Call my fiancee.
결혼식은 예정대로 진행할 테니
아무것도 취소하지 말라고 전해요
And tell her that the wedding's still on.
And don't cancel anything.
콜롬비아 보고타의 집으로
내가 곧 간다고 전해 주쇼
Tell her I'll be back home
in Bogota, Colombia real soon.
그래, 알았다
Yeah, right.
MONK Season 4 Epi. 16
Mr. Monk Gets Jury Duty
토니 샬롭
(에이드리안 몽크 役)
트레일러 하워드
(나탈리 티거 役)
제이슨 그레이 스탠포드
(랜달 디셔 경위 役)
테드 리바인
(리랜드 스토틀마이어 경감 役)
자막제작 - NSC 자막팀
(http://club.nate.com/tsm)
딕테이션
김철균(kim1047@nate.com)
싱크편집
최자앵(ashaa@nate.com)
한글번역
홍관호(kwanho_hong@nate.com)
한글교정
임재영(dreamimage@nate.com)
ORIGINAL AIR DATE ON USA: 2006/03/17
저 왔어요
Good morning.
편지가 왔네요
뭐 하고 계세요?
Picked up your mail.
What is going on?
재미 좀 보고 있죠
난 정말 이게 좋아요
I'm having fun.
I love this stuff.
네. 제 눈에도 보이네요
Yeah, so I see.
난 대개는 악수하는 걸
좋아하지 않지만
You know, I usually
don't like shaking hands,
터퍼웨어(식품 보존 용기)를
발명한 사람을 만나면
but I ever met the man
invented Tupperware,
기꺼이 악수를 하겠어요
I would shake his hand.
아마 세상을 떠났을걸요
I think he might be dead.
뭐, 그래도 악수할래요
분명 완벽하게 보존되어 있을 테니까요
Well, I would still shake his hand,
because he's probably perfectly preserved.
봐요, 이 밀폐되는 것 좀 보라고요
All right, look.
It's virtually airtight. Look at this.
- 이런
- 이런이라뇨?
- Uh-oh.
- Uh-oh what?
아무것도 아니에요
나중에 보여 드릴게요
Uh-oh nothing.
I'll show you later.
뭔데요?
뭔데 그래요?
What?
What, what is that?
걱정 마세요. 출두하려면
아직 몇 주 남았어요
Don't worry, you don't have to
report for weeks.
출두를 하다뇨?
Report for what?
내가 징집된 건가요?
I've been drafted?
징집 통지서를 보낸 거군요
They've reinstated the draft.
그럼 이제 벌거벗은 사람들과...
샤워를 해야 하겠군요
I'm gonna have to shower with...
naked people, naked.
벌거벗은... 남자들과...
Naked naked...
men with...
몽크 씨, 징집되신 게 아니라
배심원 소환장이 온 거예요
Mr. Monk, you're not being drafted.
You have jury duty!
오, 살았다
Oh, my god.
이런, 세상에
- 분명 내가 뽑힐 거예요
- 몽크 씬 안 뽑힐 거예요
- I'm gonna get picked.
- Mr. Monk, you're not gonna get picked.
몽크 씬 전직 경찰이셨고
현역에 계신 친구 분들도 많잖아요
You're ex-police officer.
You have tons of friends on the force.
나도 재판에 많이 참석해 봤는데
전직 경찰은 항상 뽑힌다고요
I've been to plenty of trials.
Ex-cops get picked all the time.
아직도 수리 중이라니
정말 믿을 수가 없네요
I can't believe they're still
renovating this place.
차라리 "세금 낭비 중"이라고
표지판을 붙이든가
They should put up a sign,
"your tax dollars not at work."
몽크 씨, 왜 안 오세요?
Mr. Monk, you're not moving.
- 내가 안 가고 있나요?
- 네, 그렇네요
- I'm not?
- No, you're not.
자요
Here we go.
자, 발 떼시고요
Here we go. Go on.
좋아요
Here you go.
걷고 계시네요
착하셔라
You're walking.
Look at you.
정말 자랑스러워요
I'm so proud of you.
난 뽑히고 말 거예요
I'm gonna get picked.
이쪽으로 통과해 주시겠어요?
Take that please?
- 여기 있습니다
- 고맙습니다
- Here you go.
- Thank you.
몽크 씨, 허리띠를 끄르셔야 해요
Mr. Monk, you're gonna have
to take off your belt.
아, 뭐 어차피 가려던 참이었어요
Ah, I was going to anyway.
목매달러 말이에요
To hang myself.
오해하진 말아요
이건 훌륭한 시스템이니까요
Don't get me wrong,
it's a great system.
정말 세상에서 가장 훌륭한
사법 체계죠 / 저도 동의해요
It really is the best justice system
in the world. / I agree.
난 그저 거기 참여하고 싶지
않을 뿐이에요
I just don't wanna be a part of it.
몽크 씨, 사람들 모두가 그런
생각을 하면 대체 어떻게 되겠어요?
Mr. Monk, what if everybody
felt that way?
다 그렇게 생각해요
Everybody does.
몽크 씨, 전 이해가 안 가요
Mr. Monk, I don't understand.
몽크 씨는 범죄와 싸우는 데
헌신해 오셨잖아요. 그렇죠?
You've dedicated your life
to fighting crimes, right?
수수께끼를 풀고
죄인들을 감옥에 보내면서요?
Solving mysteries,
sending guilty people to jail?
여기서도 하실 수 있어요
배심원이 하는 것도 그거랑 똑같아요
Well, you can do that here.
That's what juries do. It's the same thing.
- 난 혼자 일해요. 혼자가 좋다고요
- 혼자가 좋다고요?
- But I work alone. I'm a lone wolf.
- You're a lone wolf?
현역에 있었을 때도, 난 파트너가
있는 걸 그다지 좋아하지 않았어요
Even when I was the force,
I didn't really like having a partner.
난 다른 사람과 일을 못한다고요
I can't work with other people.
네. 하지만 좀 슬프게 들리네요
Okay, well, I think that's kind of sad.
맞아요. 아주 슬픈 일이죠
I agree. That's very sad.
전 몽크 씨가 뽑혔으면 좋겠어요
몽크 씨에게도 도움이 될 거예요
You know, I hope you do get picked.
I think it'd be good for you.
- 그런 말 말아요
- 다른 사람들과 함께 일하면서
Don't say that. / You know,
you work with different kinds of people.
의견도 들어 보고, 논쟁도 하고
타협도 하다 보면 말이에요
You know, you listen to their opinions,
argue, compromise.
고마워요, 나탈리
무슨 뜻인지는 잘 알겠지만
Thank you, Natalie.
I, I know you mean well.
차라리 비행기 창문에 빨려 나가
떨어지는 편이 낫겠어요
I'd rather be sucked
out of an airplane window.
안녕하십니까? 샌프란시스코 경찰청에서
생방송으로 보내 드립니다
Good afternoon, I am live from in front of
San Francisco police department.
봐요, 경감님이세요
Look, it's the captain.
지금 미겔 에스코바가 기소인부절차를
마치고 돌아오길 기다리고 있습니다
We're here waiting for Miguel Escobar
to return from his pre-trial arraignment.
저기 오고 있군요!
경사님, 스토틀마이어 경사님!
Here he is!
Sergeant, sergeant Stottlemeyer!
- 한 말씀 해주시겠습니까?
- 할 말 없습니다
- Excuse me, can we get a word, please?
- No comment.
그리고! 저는 경감입니다
Actually, it's "captain."
스토틀마이어 경감님이십니다
'T' 자가 3번 들어가죠
Yeah, captain Leland Stottlemeyer,
with three T's,
'경감(captain)'의 T자까지
더하면 4개군요
four,
if you count the one in "captain."
에스코바는 두 번이나 탈출한 전력이
있는데, 또 탈출 시도를 할까요?
Escobar has already escaped twice.
Do you think he'll try again?
그럴 수 없도록 만반의 준비를
하고 있습니다
We're taking every precaution to avoid that.
지난번에도 그렇게
말씀하시지 않았나요?
Isn't that what they said last time?
지난번에는 내가 책임자가 아니었죠
I wasn't in charge last time.
안녕하세요?
모두 기명하셨겠죠?
Hello. Did everybody sign in?
호명을 받는 분은
내일 아침 9시에
If I call your name,
you are required to come back
다시 이곳으로 오신 다음
tomorrow morning at 9 A.M.
302호로 가시면 됩니다
and report to room 302.
호명을 받지 못하시는 분은
If you do not hear your name...
제외되신 겁니다
you are excused.
드디어 시작이군요
Here it comes.
- 에이드리안 몽크 씨!
- 그럴 줄 알았어요
- Adrian Monk!
- There it is.
그렇지!
Yes!
바쁘신가요?
Is this a bad time?
네, 이제 바빠졌소
Yeah, it is now.
랜디, 라피데스 특수 요원은 알고 있겠지?
Randy, you remember special agent Lapides.
사실은 혼자 온 게 아닙니다
법무 장관님과 함께 왔죠
Actually, I'm not alone.
I'm here with the attorney general.
미합중국 법무 장관님 말인가요?
The attorney general of the United states?
여기 계십니다
읽어 보시겠소?
He's in here. You wanna read it?
읽을 필요 없소
에스코바는 못 넘깁니다
I don't need to read it.
I'm not giving you Escobar.
절대 못 넘겨요
No way, no how.
리랜드, 이건 샌프란시스코에
국한되는 사건이 아닙니다
Leland, this case is bigger
than San Francisco.
- 놈은 7개 주에 마약을 공급하고 있었어요
- 네. 하지만 우리가 놈을 잡았죠
- Escobar was supplying drugs to seven states.
- Yeah, but we caught him here.
맞습니다. 그리고 우린
살인죄로 체포했소
Damn right we did,
and we got him on homicide.
바로 여기 샌프란시스코에서요
Right here in the city of San Francisco.
내가 3년이나 공들인 사건이란 말입니다
This case represents three years in my life.
국가를 대신해 심심한 감사를 드립니다
Well, you have thanks for the great nation.
하지만 다 결정된 사안입니다
연방에서 기소하기로 결정이 났어요
But it's a done deal.
A federal indictment's already been filed.
- 연방에서 먼저 재판할 겁니다
- 망할 자식들
- We're gonna try him first.
- Sons of bitches.
목요일에 도망자 인도 심리가 열립니다
There's an extradition hearing on Thursday.
이렇게 진행하도록 하시죠
Here's how it's gonna work.
그때까지 에스코바를 맡고 계시다가
그날 법원으로 호송을 하시고
You baby-sit Escobar until then.
You bring him to courthouse,
로비에서 우리 측에 인도하신 다음
집으로 돌아가시면 됩니다
we meet you in the lobby,
you drop the mob, you go home.
뭐라고 말씀하셨죠, 장관님?
네, 그렇게 전하겠습니다
What's that, sir?
Yeah. I'll tell him.
법무 장관님께서 말씀하시길
The attorney general says,
망치지 말고 잘 하랍니다
"don't screw it up."
도트리 씨, 여길 보니 전에 3번이나
배심원 선발에서 제외되셨군요?
Mr. Daughtry, it says here you've been
excused from jury duty three times before?
네, 사업이 바빠서요
Yeah, I got a business to run.
그럼 사업을 대신 봐줄
사람을 찾아보세요
Well, you're going to
find someone else to run it.
변호인 측도, 검찰 측도, 그리고 나도
귀하를 배심원으로 받아들입니다
The defense accepts you,
so does the prosecution. So do I.
자리에 앉으세요
귀하를 10번 배심원으로 명합니다
Have a seat.
You're juror number 10.
좋습니다. 다음 분 일어나세요
Okay, next stand up.
이름을 말씀하세요
State your name.
- 나탈리 티거입니다
- 철자를 말씀하세요
- Uh, Natalie Teeger.
- Spell it.
아뇨, 제가 소환된 게 아닙니다
Oh, no, I wasn't called.
이쪽은 제 비서입니다, 판사님
She's my assistant, your honor.
그럼 귀하는...
And you are...
에이드리안 몽크입니다
Adrian Monk.
대문자 A, 소문자 d, 소문자 r, 소문자 i
소문자 a, 소문자 n, 한 칸 띄고...
Capital A. small D, small R, small I,
small A, small N. Space.
고맙습니다, 몽크 씨
우리도 알 것 같군요
Thank you, Mr. Monk.
I think we have it.
판사님...
Your honor...
안타깝지만 이번 배심 의무는
수행하지 못할 것 같습니다
I will not be able to serve
today unfortunately.
여러 가지 이유가 있는데
첫 번째로는...
For a number of reasons.
First off...
화장실 문제가 있습니다
There's the bathroom situation.
저는 다른 사람과 화장실을
못 씁니다. 정말입니다
I can't share a bathroom.
I just can't.
나탈리한테 물어보세요
나탈리?
You can ask Natalie. Natalie?
네, 까다로운 분이세요
정말 까다로운 분이죠
Yeah, he's persnickety.
He's very persnickety.
완전 까다로움 그 자체라니까요
He's persnickety squared.
그리고 음식을 먹을 때도
특별한 제약이 있습니다
And I have special dietary needs, your honor.
저는 제 앞에서 직접 조리된
음식만 먹을 수 있습니다
I can't eat food
unless I actually see it being prepared.
사실입니다, 판사님
That's true, your honor.
다른 건 없습니까?
Anything else?
있습니다
Yes, sir.
제 집에는 저만 바라보고 사는
식물이 둘 있습니다
I have two plants at home that are
completely dependent on me, your honor.
식물이라고요?
Plants.
고사리 하나와...
아담한 진달래 덤불이 있습니다
I have a fern
and a small azalea bush.
비서를 두고 계시니
물을 주라고 시키면 되잖습니까?
And you have an assistant.
Can't she water the plants?
좋은 지적이십니다만
문제가 좀 있습니다
Good question. Here's the thing.
제 비서는 물을 과다하게
주는 경향이 있습니다
She has a tendency to overwater.
그렇지 않아요
딱 한 번 그랬잖아요
Okay, that is not true.
That happened once.
- 한 번 이상이잖아요
- 겨우 2온스였어요
- More than once.
- It was two ounces.
진달래 덤불에 2온스면
거의 수영장이나 마찬가지죠
Two ounces to an azalea bush...
That would be like a swimming pool.
잠깐만요...
Okay, wait...
몽크 씨, 배심 의무를 피하려 이런저런
핑계를 대는 사람을 수도 없이 봐 왔지만
Mr. Monk, I have seen hundreds of people
pretend to be disturbed to avoid jury duty,
귀하의 핑계는 단연 최우수감이군요
but you, sir, are in a class by yourself.
- 정말 너그러우십니다
- 하지만 통하지 않을 겁니다
- You're too kind.
- Well, it's not gonna work, sir.
- 배심원으로 명합니다, 몽크 씨
- 이의 있습니다
- You have a seat, Mr. Monk.
- Objection.
몽크 씨는 11번 배심원입니다
You're juror number 11.
괜찮습니다, 파머 씨
편하게 하십시오
It's okay, Mr. Palmer.
Take your time.
정확히 어디를 찔렸는지
보여 주실 수 있겠습니까?
Could you show us exactly
where you were stabbed?
바로 여기 허벅지입니다
Right here in the thigh.
몽크 씨, 보셔야죠!
Mr. Monk, you have to look!
11번 배심원! 증거를 똑바로
보시기 바랍니다
Number 11, evidence is
presented, sir, for you.
찔린 다음 어떻게 하셨습니까?
What did you do then?
너무 피가 많이 나서
I was bleeding pretty bad
제 차 바닥에 예전부터 있던
수건을 움켜쥐었습니다
so I grabbed an old towel out of my car.
There was one on the floor.
그리고 상처에 대고 눌렀습니다
And I pressed it against the wound.
누구 전화입니까?
Whose phone was that?
저 여자 분입니다, 판사님
3번 배심원요
It's hers, your honor, number 3.
그리고 저 여자 분은 졸았습니다
And she fell asleep.
- 네, 맞아요. 8번 배심원입니다
- 아무도 고자질쟁이는 좋아하지 않습니다
- Yeah, you. Number 8, your honor.
- Nobody likes a tattletale, Mr. Monk.
제 생각엔 9번 배심원이
고자질쟁이인 것 같습니다
I think number 9 is a tattletale.
그만하면 됐습니다, 몽크 씨
That'll do, Mr. Monk.
계속하세요, 폭스 씨
Proceed, Mr. Fox.
찔린 다음에 무슨 일이 일어났습니까?
What happened after you were stabbed?
그 남자가 제 돈 봉투를 가지고
달아났습니다
He grabbed my deposit envelope
and took off.
칼 씨, 휴게소에서 증인을 찌르고
Carl, is the person that stabbed you
at that rest stop,
돈을 빼앗아 달아난 사람이
지금 이 법정 안에 있습니까?
took your money and ran away,
in this court room today?
그렇습니다
Yes, sir.
바로 저 사람입니다
He's right there.
뭐 하는 겁니까?
What are you doing?
물티슈를 드려야 해서요, 판사님
He needs a wipe, your honor.
앉으세요, 티거 씨
자리에 앉으세요!
Sit down, miss Teeger.
Sit down.
또다시 배심을 방해하면
Now, if you interfere with the jury again,
재판 방해 및 법정 모욕으로
체포하겠습니다. 알겠습니까?
I will have you arrested for tampering
and contempt, understand?
네, 판사님. 죄송합니다
Yes, sir. Sorry.
증인이 피고인 로버트 페리를
지목했다고 기록해 주시기 바랍니다
Let the record show that the witness
has identified the defendant, Robert Perry.
아이고, 골치야...
Oh, my god.
휴대폰은 반입 금지입니다
끝나면 돌려 드리겠습니다
No cell phones are allowed.
You'll get them back when you're done.
저는 복도에 있을 테니
필요하시면 버저를 울리세요
I'll be down the hallway
if you need me, just ring the buzzer.
고맙습니다. 고맙습니다
Thank you. Thank you.
고마워요. 좋습니다
Thank you. Okay.
어떻게 생각하세요?
What did you think?
- 저는 상당히 흥미롭던데요
- 아주 흥미롭더군요
- I thought it was pretty interesting.
- Very interesting.
노트 필기를 세 권이나 했어요
I filled up three notebooks.
뭐 하세요?
What are you doing?
모양을 똑같이 만드는 겁니다
I'm just making them even.
그래야 우리 모두 집중을 할 수 있죠
So we can all concentrate.
블라인드가 똑바르지 않으면
정신이 산만해질 수 있으니까요
And not be distracted
by uneven Venetian blinds.
자, 여러분. 시작합시다
Okay, everyone, let's get stared.
제가 배심원을 해 본 경험이 있으니
And I've done this before, so, uh,
반대가 없으시다면 제가
배심장을 하도록 하겠습니다
I would be glad to be our foreman
if there are no objections.
네. 그러세요 / 좋습니다. 그럼
모두 자리에 앉도록 하죠
No. No. / All right, great, well,
let's all have a seat.
순서대로 앉는 게 가장 좋으므로
Actually, it'd be be best
if we all sat in order.
괜찮으시다면, 제가 7번이니까...
If you don't mind, I'm
juror number 7 and...
이쪽 방향으로 8번부터
차례로 앉으시죠
we go this way, number 8...
and so forth.
좋습니다
Okay, great.
행복해 보이는구려
You look happy.
아주 흥미로운 경험입니다
진짜 미국인이 된 기분이에요
This is very exciting for me.
I feel like a real American.
- 실례합니다 / 네?
- 저랑 자리를 바꿔 주실 수 있을까요?
Excuse me? Yeah?
Do you mind if we traded seats?
왜요?
Why?
저는 10번이 되고 싶거든요
제가 가장 좋아하는 숫자랍니다
I'd rather be number 10,
my favorite number.
제겐 중요한 일이에요
It's kind of important to me.
저 사람이 자리를 바꾸려고 해요
이보쇼, 형씨?
Look, the guy is trying to change seats.
You know what, pal?
아무도 당신이랑 안 바꿀 거요
그러니 앉으쇼. 알았어요?
Nobody's trading anything with you.
Now sit down, okay?
얌전히 앉아요. 알았소?
I mean it. Sit, okay?
예전의 경험에 의하면
So I've been on a few juries.
무기명으로 예비 투표를 해서
전체 의견을 파악하는 게
And it's customary to start off with
a preliminary vote by secret ballot,
일반적인 관례더군요
반대 의견 있으십니까?
just to see where we all are.
Any objections?
- 전혀요
- 없습니다
- Not at all.
- None.
좋습니다
Great.
- 자, 여기 있어요
- 고마워요
- Oh, here you go.
- Thanks.
담배 좀 피워도 괜찮겠습니까?
Anybody mind if I, uh, smoke?
알았어요, 알았어
꼭 내가 재판 받는 기분이군요
All right, all right, all right.
I'm not the one on trial. Okay, folks, huh?
이쪽으로 전달해 주세요
Just pass them down, please.
자, 어디 봅시다
유죄
All right, let's do this.
Guilty.
유죄
와, 쉽게 끝났네요
집에서 저녁을 먹을 수 있겠어요
Wow, that was easy.
Guess I'll be home for dinner.
잠깐, 11장밖에 안 되는군요
투표 안 하신 분?
Wait a minute. That was only 11.
Who didn't vote?
얼룩이 져서요
Smudge.
돌겠군
You gotta be kidding.
- 고맙습니다
- 천만에요
- Thank you.
- It's no problem.
무죄
Not guilty.
그럼 11대 1이 되는군요
That makes it 11 to 1.
꼭 이런 사람이 있다니까
There's always one, isn't there?
Always one.
- 정말 무죄라고 생각하세요?
- 모르겠습니다
- Do you really think he's not guilty?
- I don't know.
당연히 유죄죠
증거를 봐요
Of course he's guilty.
Look at the evidence.
칼을 발견했잖아요
흉기로 쓴 칼이 배낭에 있었다고요
They found the knife,
the knife he used in his knapsack.
게다가 피해자도 범인을 지목했어요
또 뭐가 더 필요하다는 거죠?
Plus the victim identified him.
I mean, what more do you want?
글쎄요, 뭔가 더 있다는
느낌이 듭니다
I have no, I have a feeling
there's more to it.
감이 와요
It's a feeling.
잠시 생각할 시간을
주셨으면 좋겠습니다
I would just like to
think about it for a while.
생각할 게 뭐가 있어요?
What there left to think about?
유죄가 맞다니까
He's guilty.
모두 조용히 해 주시면 좋겠습니다
I'm gonna need you all to be quiet.
- 그래, 형씨나 조용히 하시지
- 조용히 하라고요?!
- Yeah, you get quiet.
- Quiet!
집중을 하려는 겁니다
Concentrate.
잠시 왔다 갔다 걸으면서
신중히 검토한 다음에
I'm gonna walk around now.
And pace back and forth.
준비가 되면 답을 말씀드릴게요
원래 그렇게 하는 겁니다
Then, when I'm ready, I'll tell you
the solution. That's how it works.
아뇨
그렇게는 안 돼요
No.
No way.
여긴 당신 혼자 있는 게 아니에요
우리와 상의를 해야죠
You're not alone here.
You have to talk to us.
- 무슨 생각인지 우리한테 말을 해요
- 난 그런 식으로 일하지 않아요
- Tell us what you're thinking.
- That's not how I do it.
난 나만의 방법이 있어요
신이 주신 축복이자 저주죠
I have a system.
It's a gift and a curse.
실은 말이죠, 난 파트너와
일하는 걸 좋아하지 않아요
Here's the thing,
I don't like working with partners.
마음에 드시든, 안 드시든
여기 11명의 파트너가 있습니다
Well, like it or not,
you've got 11 partners now.
집중해서 들어
한 번만 얘기할 거야
Pay attention,
I'm only gonna say this once.
에스코바의 심리는 내일 정오에 열린다
Escobar's hearing is tomorrow at 12 noon.
오늘 밤 자정에 이 건물의
출입문과 창문을 모두 잠근 다음
We lock this joint down tonight
at midnight, every exit, every window.
새벽 1시에 바닥부터 천장까지
철저히 폭발물 탐색을 할 거야
1 A.M., we sweep for bombs.
Head to toe.
오전 6시에 이 건물과
옆 건물 옥상에 저격수를 배치해
6 A.M., I want snipers on this roof
and on the roof next door.
우린 11시 30분에 도착해서
We arrive 11:30.
11시 40분에 엘리베이터에서
라피데스를 만나 놈을 인계한다
11:40, we meet Lapides at the elevator
and hand him off.
그러고 나면, 우린 손을 터는 거지
After that, he's the bureau's headache.
- 경감님, 다시 말씀해 주시겠어요?
- 그러지. 어느 부분?
- Sir, could you repeat that, please?
- Yeah, what part?
어... "집중해서 들어. 한 번만
얘기할 거야" 다음부터 전부요
Uh, everything after "Pay attention,
I'm only gonna say this once."
- 증거물 15B입니다
- 고맙습니다
- Exhibit 15B.
- Thank you.
뭘 하는 겁니까?
What's he doing now?
우리도 모르겠습니다
We're not sure.
판사님께 말씀은 전하셨나요?
Did you talk to the judge?
이미 늦었다고 하시더군요
예비 배심원을 이미 돌려보내셨대요
He says it's too late.
He's already sent the alternates home.
된통 걸리셨네요
You're stuck with him.
- 조심하세요
- 고맙습니다
- Bless you.
- Thank you.
실례합니다
Excuse me.
- 이걸 좀 입어 주시겠어요?
- 뭘 하시려고요?
- Would you mind trying these on?
- What for?
피해자와 키가 비슷하시잖아요
뭘 좀 확인하고 싶어서 그럽니다
You're about the same height of the victim,
and I just want to try something.
잠깐이면 됩니다
It'll just take a minute.
뭘 하시려고?
패션쇼라도 하시려고?
What do you got? A fashion show, huh?
정말 못 말리겠군
I can't believe this guy.
우린 이 옷이 피해자가 공격당했을 때
입었던 바지라는 걸 알고 있습니다
We know these are the pants the victim
was wearing when he was attacked.
의자에 올라가 주시겠어요?
Could you step up, please?
보시다시피 칼이 바지를 뚫고
들어갔습니다만
Of course, you can see
where the knife went through the fabric.
뭔가 말이 안 되는 점이 있습니다
Well, something doesn't add up.
제가 보기에 파머 씨는 바지를
내려 입는 걸 좋아하더군요
I notice Mr. Palmer likes
to wear his pants low.
법정에서 우린 거의 파머 씨의...
In the courtroom, we could
almost see his...
아래 부위를...
뒤쪽 대퇴부를...
bottom part.
Rear posterior, side...
엉덩이 말이죠?
His butt?
고맙습니다
Thank you.
상처를 좀 보시죠
Look at the wound.
파머 씨는 허벅지 위쪽을 찔렸어요
He was actually stabbed in the upper thigh.
- 일치하지 않습니다
- 그렇네요. 저것 좀 봐요
- It doesn't match up.
- He's right, look at that.
적어도, 서 있을 때 찔린 건 아닙니다
의자에 앉아 주시겠어요?
At least, not when he's standing.
Could you have a seat, please?
나쁜 자식
앉아 있었군요
Son of a bitch.
He was sitting down.
그게 어쨌다는 거죠?
What does that prove?
파머 씨는 칼에 찔릴 때 서 있었다고
말했어요 / 거짓말을 했군요
Mr. Palmer said he was standing up
when he was stabbed. / He was lying.
파머 씨는 휴게소에 차를 댄 후
로버트 페리 씨가 자고 있는 걸 보고
I think he pulled into that rest stop,
saw Robert Perry who was sleeping,
스스로 자기 다리를 찌른 다음
돈을 챙긴 것 같습니다
stabbed himself,
pocketted the money,
그리고 페리 씨에게
전부 덮어씌운 거죠
and then blamed everything on Perry.
난 무죄 쪽으로 바꾸겠어요
I'm switching my vote...
to not guilty.
나 참... / 말도 안 돼요
왜 자기 다릴 찌르겠어요?
Oh, come on. / What? That is ridiculous?
Why would he stab himself?
우린... 우린 이분 말씀을
경청해야 합니다
We, we, we should listen to this man.
이분은 우리 모두의 의견에 맞선
용감한 분이셨습니다
He was a very brave man
to stand up against us all.
DNA 증거는 어쩌고요?
그걸 무시할 순 없습니다
What about the DNA evidence?
You can't just ignore that.
페리 씨의 칼에
피해자의 피가 묻었잖아요
Found victim's blood on Perry's knife?
그게 페리 씨의 칼이란 걸 어떻게 알죠?
페리 씨는 처음 보는 칼이랬습니다
How do we know it was Robert Perry's knife?
He denied ever seeing it.
당연히 자기 칼이 아니라고 하지
그럼 대체 뭐라고 할 것 같소?
Of course he denied it.
What the hell do you expect?
- 지문도 찍혀 있지 않았어요
- 닦아 냈으니까 그랬겠지
- Well, his prints weren't on it.
- Well, then, he wiped them off, huh?
봐요, 이게 그놈 배낭이란 말입니다!
Look, it was in his knapsack!
대체 무슨 놈의 탐정이 그따위야?
What the hell kind of a detective are you?
왜 칼날의 피는 닦지 않고
손잡이만 닦았는지를
I'm the kind of detective who wonders
why someone would take the time
궁금해하는 탐정이라고 해 두죠
to wipe down the handle,
but not the blade.
게다가 시간대도 전부 이상합니다
Also, the timeline is all wrong.
로버트 페리는 폭행이 일어나고
한 시간 후에 체포되었어요
Robert Perry was picked up
an hour after the assault.
- 현장에서 2마일도 채 못 가서요
- 그게 어쨌다는 겁니까?
- Less than two miles from there.
- So what?
도망을 가던 게 아니었단 겁니다
He wasn't running away.
만약 내가 누군가를 찔렀다면...
If I had just stabbed somebody...
- 누군가 저 방수포를 옮겼어요
- 뭐라고요?
- Somebody moved that tarp.
- Excuse me?
저 아래 방수포로 덮인
쓰레기 수납기가 있는데
There is a dumpster down there
with a tarp in it.
어제는 방수포가 돌돌 말린 상태로
한쪽 옆으로 치워져 있었거든요
Yesterday the tarp was rolled up
and draped over the side.
그게 우리들이나 이 사건과
무슨 관계가 있죠? / 전혀 없죠
What does it have to do with us
or this case? / Or anything?
미안해요. 여러분 말씀이 맞습니다
I'm sorry, you're right.
You're right.
자, 다음은 뭐죠?
돈! 그래요, 돈입니다
Okay, what's next? The money.
Okay, the money.
돈은 어떻게 됐을까요?
What happened to the money?
- 땅에 묻었을 수도 있죠
- 석회야!
- Maybe he buried it.
- Lime.
누군가 방수포 위에
온통 석회를 뿌려 놨어요
Somebody poured lime all over that tarp.
저 아래 시체가 있는 것 같아요
I think there's a body down there.
나 원, 이제 집에는 다 갔군요
Oh, we're never getting out of here.
- 안녕하세요. 11번입니다
- 네, 알고 있습니다
- Hello, I'm number 11.
- Yeah, I remember.
미친 소리로 들리시겠지만
저 아래 있는 쓰레기 수납기 말입니다
I know this sounds crazy,
but there's a dumpster downstairs.
경찰견이 냄새를 맡고
돌아다니는 걸 봤거든요
I saw a police dog sniffing around.
아마 저 파란 방수포 밑에
시체가 있어서 그런 것 같아요
I think there's a body under that blue tarp.
리엔조 판사님이 당신을
주의해서 지켜보라고 하셨어요
Judge Rienzo said I should
keep an eye on you.
당신이 배심 결정을 지연하거나
방해하면 보고하라고 하셨죠
He said to report you
if you cause any delay or disruption.
- 지금 그러고 계신 겁니까?
- 아닙니다
- Is that what you're doing?
- No.
아뇨, 아뇨
No, no, no.
나탈리!
Natalie!
몽크 씨, 저녁 가지고 왔어요!
아래층에 맡겨 놓을게요!
Mr. Monk, I brought your dinner!
I'm gonna leave it downstairs!
- 쓰레기 수납기요!
- 뭐라고요?
- Dumpster!
- What?
쓰레기 수납기!
Dumpster!
나탈리예요
It's Natalie.
쓰레기 수납기에 시체가 있어요!
There's a body in the dumpster!
먼스터에서 뜨거운 타디를 사 오라고요?
You want a hot toddy at Munster?
전 코브 샐러드를 싸 왔는데요!
I brought a cobb salad!
쓰레기 수납기에 시체가 있다고요!
There's a body the dumpster!
코브 샐러드를 싸 왔다고요!
I just got the cobb salad!
무슨 소릴 하는 거예요?
What are you talking about?
몽크 씨야말로 무슨 말씀이세요?
저기 죽은 사람의...
There is a...
dead....
시체가...
쓰레기 수납기에 있다고요!
body...
in the dumpster.
스토틀마이어 경감님께 전화해요!
Call captain Stottlemeyer!
잠깐... 시체라고요?
Okay, wait, a body?
알았어요, 알았어
Okay, okay, okay, okay.
이 사람 말은 경청할 필요가 없어요
We should not listen to this man.
이 사람이 미국을 다 망치고 있어요
He is ruining America for everybody.
다시 들어 봅시다
Tell me again.
내 경찰 경력 중 가장 중요한 사건을
처리하던 중에 내가 불려 온 이유가...
I've been called away from the most
important case of my career because...
몽크 씨가 시체를 봤다고
말했기 때문이죠
Because Mr. Monk said he saw a body.
저 위 3층에서 말이죠
From up there. From the third floor.
그것도 다른 사건을
해결하는 와중에요
While he was deliberating
on another case.
경감님!
Captain!
시체가 있습니다
We got a body.
접근 금지선을 치도록 해
저쪽도 / 네, 경위님
Rope everything off.
That side, too. / Yes, sir.
나탈리, 아무것도 만지지 말아요
Natalie, don't touch anything.
시체에 대한 얘긴 맞았네요
Well, he was right about the body.
여러분, 저 밑에서 무슨 일이 일어났건
우리와는 상관이 없습니다
People, whatever happened down there
has nothing to do with us.
우리에겐 아직 할 일이 있습니다
We still have a job to do.
- 투표를 다시 하면 어떨까요?
- 좋은 생각입니다
- Maybe we should take another vote.
- Good idea.
각자 생각을 알아보기로 합시다
모두 앉아 주세요
Let's just see who stands where, all right?
Everybody back.
이번엔 그냥 거수로 합시다
유죄라고 생각하시는 분?
Now, just by a show of hands,
who's still voting guilty?
유죄요
Guilty.
무죄라고 생각하는 분?
Not guilty.
6대 6이군요
6 to 6.
이제 연장전에 접어들었군요
And we go into extra innings.
몽크 씨, 여자예요!
Mr. Monk, it's a woman!
약 예순 살쯤 되는 노부인이에요!
She's about 60 years old!
- 누구인가요?
- 신분증이 없어요
- Who is she?
- No ID.
- 신분증이 없대요! (No I.D.)
- 모르겠다고요? (No idea)
- No ID!
- No idea?
신분증이 없다고요!
No ID.
모르겠다 이거죠?
No idea.
신분증이 없다고요!
No ID!
모르겠다고요?
No idea?
노 (No)
No...
아이 (I)
I...
- 디! (D)
- 모르겠다고요?
- D!
- No idea.
노...
자, 이리 와요
No...
Okay, here.
아이...
I...
디!
D!
모르겠다 이거죠?
No idea?
- 신분증이 없다고요!
- 노 아이디!
- No ID!
모르겠다고?
신분증을 살펴봐!
No idea?
Check her identification!
- 신분증이 없다니까요!
- 노 아이디!!
- No ID!
- 그거 정형외과용 특수 신발이야?
- 네?
- Are those orthopedic shoes?
- What?
그 신발 말이야
정형외과용 신발이냐고?
Those shoes, orthopedic shoes.
네, 그런 것 같아요
Yeah, I think so.
대기실에서 그 노부인을 본 기억이 나
I remember I saw her
in the waiting room!
- 배심원이었을 거야!
- 뭐라고요?
- I think she's a juror!
- What?
- 배심원!
- 네?
- A juror!
- What?
- 배심원이라고!
- 저게 대체 뭐지?
- A juror!
- What the hell is that?
배심원 중 한 명이 창문에 기대서
경찰과 얘기하고 있는 것 같군요
Looks like one of your jurors leaning
out of a window talking to a police officer.
지금 이 시간 부로 저 배심단을
격리시키도록 해!
I want that jury sequestered as of now.
뭐 하는 거요?
What is it doing?
담배를 피우고 계셔서요
You were smoking.
금연실도 아니잖소
표지판을 읽어 봐요
I'm allowed to smoke.
Read the sign.
제가 잠을 못 자겠어요
It's keeping me awake.
불이 날지도 모른단 말입니다
You're gonna start a fire.
그럼 문제없는 거군
형씨는 깨어 있을 거잖아. 그렇죠?
So there's no problem.
You're awake, right?
불이 나면, 형씨가 끄면 되겠네
안 그래요?
If there is a fire,
you'll see it and put it out, right?
- 안 그래요?
- 네 / 좋아
- Hey, right?
- Right. / Right.
배심원실에서도 작작 좀 해 두쇼
Don't be such an ass in the jury room.
잘 자요
Good night.
주무세요
내일 오후 예약을 확인하고 싶어서요
I'd like to confirm a reservation
for tomorrow afternoon.
예약 번호는 X-73294번입니다
My reservation number is X 73294.
네. 보고타행 32편 비행기예요
Yes, flight 32 to Bogota.
두 명이에요. 저랑 제 남편요
The two of us, me and my husband.
4시 30분요?
4:30.
걱정 마세요. 늦지 않을 겁니다
Don't worry, we won't be late.
- 경위, 나 코가 간질거리는데
- 꿈도 꾸지 마
- Lieutenant, my nose itches.
- Forget it.
아, 뭐 상관없지
Ah, it doesn't matter.
곧 내 손으로 긁을 수 있을 테니까
I'll scratch it myself soon enough.
경감님, 놈이 방금 자기 코를
긁을 거라고 했습니다
Captain, he just said
he gonna scratch his nose.
그렇군
Okay.
놈의 말투로 봐서...
협박인 것 같습니다
The way he said it was like a threat.
자기 코를 긁겠다는 협박을 했다고?
He threatened to scratch his nose?
경위, 가서 차량이나 준비하게
이제 일을 끝내야지
Lieutenant, bring the van around.
Let's get this over with.
무죄라고 생각하는 분?
Not guilty?
- 아직 8대 4군요
- 저 시계 맞는 거죠?
- It's still 8 to 4.
- Is that clock right?
11번 배심원! 몇몇 부분은 정말
좋은 지적이었다는 거 인정해요
Number 11, you've made some really
good points. I admit that.
하지만 시간대나, 상처의 위치에 대한
얘기는 전부 추정일 뿐이에요
But everything you said about the timeline,
the location of the wound, is all circumstantial.
맞아요. 저 사람이 한 거라곤
멀쩡한 사실을 가져다가
Exactly, what he's doing is
he's taking the facts and
꽈배기처럼 뒤틀기만 했을 뿐이죠
증거를 대보란 말입니다
twisting them around like a pretzel.
Now, where's the proof, man?
증거는 필요하지 않습니다
합리적인 의심만 있으면 돼요
We don't need any proof.
All we need is a reasonable doubt.
무슨 말인지 못 알아들어요?
더 해 봐야 소용없단 뜻입니다
You know what I say?
I say we're at a deadlock.
당장 다시 법정으로 돌아가서
판결을 못 내렸다고 말하는 거예요
And I say we go back in there right now
and tell them we got a hung jury.
뭐 하는 걸까요?
What is he doing?
- 물어보기도 겁나네요
- 자, 여러분
- I'm afraid to ask.
- Excuse me.
칼 파머가 증언하기를
칼에 찔린 후에
Carl Palmer testified that
after he was stabbed,
차 바닥에 있던 이 수건을
움켜잡았다고 했어요
he grabbed this towel
off the floor of his car.
- 그리고 다리에 대고 눌렀다고 했죠
- 그런데요?
- And he pressed it against his leg.
- So?
자, 이 핏자국을 보세요
대칭을 이루고 있습니다
Well, look at the stains.
They're symmetrical.
수건을 움켜잡은 게
아닌 것 같습니다
I don't think he just grabbed the towel.
제 생각엔 아주 조심스럽게
접은 것 같아요
I think he folded it.
Very carefully.
이걸 쓰기 전에 말입니다
Before he used it.
이... 이보쇼
그래서 뭐 어쨌다는 겁니까?
You know...
You, you know, so what?
- 깔끔한 걸 좋아했나 보죠
- 고통이 심했을 텐데요
- The guy was a neatnik.
- He was in pain.
막 칼에 찔린 상태였으니까요
그런 상황에서 수건을 접는 사람은 없죠
He'd just been stabbed.
Nobody would stop to fold a towel.
맞는 말이군요
That's right.
자기 허벅지를 찌르기 전에
수건을 접어놓은 거예요
He folded the towel
before he stabbed himself.
분명 자해를 한 겁니다
저는 납득했습니다
It was definitely self-inflicted.
I'm convinced.
저도요
무죄네요
Me too.
Not guilty.
고맙습니다
Thank you.
당신은요?
What about you?
- 무죄요
- 이제 됐네요
- Not guilty.
- Here we go.
다시 투표를 해 보죠 / 물론입니다
무죄라고 생각하시는 분?
I'd like another vote. / Absolutely.
All of those voting not guilty?
- 저는 유죄 쪽으로 바꾸겠어요
- 네? / 왜요?
- I'm switching my vote to guilty.
- What? / Why?
이 수건을 봤잖아요?
What, what, what about the towel?
제겐 별 의미가 없어 보이네요
결과는 11대 1이군요
It means nothing to me.
The vote's 11 to 1.
어디 가십니까?
Where are you going?
화장실에요
무슨 문제 있나요?
To the bathroom.
You got a problem with that?
저게 믿어지세요?
Can you believe that?
아뇨, 안 믿기네요
No, I can't.
과학 선생님이라고 하셨죠?
You're a science teacher, right?
이게 제가 생각하는 게 맞나요?
Is it what I think it is?
- 석회네요
- 저도 그렇게 생각했어요
- It's lime.
- That's what I thought.
내 생각엔 12번 배심원이
쓰레기 수납기 속의 여잘 죽인 것 같아요
I think number 12 murdered
that woman in the dumpster.
왜요?
Why?
배심원으로 참여할
필요가 있었으니까요
She needed to get on a jury.
대기실에서 어떤 여자 분과
얘기하는 걸 본 기억이 납니다
I remember her talking to a woman
in the assembly room.
아마 가족이나 찾는 사람이 없을
혼자 사는 사람을 찾고 있었던 것 같아요
I think she was looking for someone
who lived alone with no family,
who wouldn't be missed.
배심원에 참여하려고 사람을 죽여요?
그런 일은 또 처음이네요
Killing somebody to get on a jury?
That's a first.
- 종일 시계만 쳐다보고 있던데
- 맞습니다
- She's been looking at that clock all day.
- That's right.
뭔가... 뭔가를 기다리고 있는 겁니다
판결을 지연시키는 거예요
She's, She's waiting for something.
She's stalling us.
판결 내용 따윈 관심도 없는 거죠
She doesn't care what the verdict is.
어떤 방향으로 결론이 나도
그 여잔 반대표를 던질 겁니다
Whatever way we vote,
she will vote the opposite.
하지만 처음 투표에선
우리와 같은 표를 던졌어요
But in the first ballot,
she voted with us.
하지만 그 여잔 제 옆에 앉아 있었어요
But she was sitting next to me.
분명 제가 쓴 내용을 보고
반대표를 던진 겁니다
She must have seen how I was voting
and went the other way.
- 저는 믿을 수 없어요
- 증명할 수 있어요
- I don't believe it.
- I can prove it, I think.
하지만 여러분의 도움이 필요합니다
But I'm gonna need your help.
그건 안 됩니다
단지 그런 이유 때문에...
No, wait a minute.
We can't just...
어제는 우리 모두가
파트너라고 말씀하셨잖습니까?
Yesterday, you said we were partners.
이건 저 혼자 힘으로는 못합니다
I can't do this alone.
제가 놓친 내용이 있나요?
What'd I miss?
막 토의를 했는데요...
Well, we were just talking and...
그게...
Well...
다시 생각해 본 결과
당신 말이 맞다는 결론을 내렸습니다
we thought about it and
we decided that you were right.
유죄예요
He's guilty.
- 정말요?
- 네. 모두 의견을 바꿀 거예요
- Really?
- Yeah, we're all changing our vote.
- 자, 공식적으로 결정합시다
- 좋습니다
- In fact, let's make it official.
- Right.
유죄라고 생각하시는 분?
Who's voting guilty?
아직 결정을 못 내렸어요
시간을 좀 주세요
I'm undecided. I...
Just give me a few minutes.
그게 무슨 말입니까?
What are you up to?
난 내 생각을 바꿀 권리가 있어요
I have every right to change my mind.
집행관을 부를 때가 된 것 같군요
I think it's time to call the bailiff.
자리에 앉아, 11번
아직 안 끝났어
Have a seat, number 11.
We're still deliberating.
11번에게 고맙단 말을 해야겠군
Number 11, I have to thank you.
이 방 안을 하루 반 동안 계속
논쟁하게끔 만들어야 했거든
I had to keep everybody here in this room
busy arguing for a day and a half.
어떻게 해야 할까 걱정했는데
당신 덕분에 일이 쉬워졌어
I wasn't sure how I was gonna do it,
but you made it easy.
- 별말씀을
- 왜 이러는 겁니까?
- Don't mention it.
- Why are you doing this?
애인을 탈출시키려는 겁니다
She's helping her boyfriend escape.
이 건물 안으로 들어올
방법이 필요했던 거예요
She had to have a way
to get into this building.
남의 눈은 피하는 게 좋겠지?
How about a little privacy, huh?
똑바르지 않아요
똑바르지 않...
Not even.
It's not even...
- 닥쳐!
- 똑바르지 않아요
- Shut up!
- It's not even.
진작부터 당신 입을 막고 싶었어
I've been waiting a long time to do this.
똑바르지 않은데...
It's not even.
위층은 살펴봤소?
천장 형태가...
Listen, did you check upstairs?
There is a drop ceiling...
그게 뭐든, 경감님
우리가 알아서 합니다
Whatever it is, captain,
We got it covered.
좋아요
Okay.
- 뭡니까?
- 인도 확인증입니다
- What's that?
- It's your receipt.
기념품으로 보관하시죠
Why don't you keep it as a souvenir?
저럴 리가 없는데?
What's going on?
몽크 씨, 괜찮으세요?
Mr. Monk, are you okay?
어머나, 이게 무슨 일이야!
Oh, my god. Oh, my god.
몽크 씨, 무슨 일이에요?
Mr. Monk, what happened?
뭐라고요? 잠깐만요
What? Hold on.
네? 뭐라고요?
What? What?
제발 부탁이니 테이프를 세게
확 떼지 말라고 말하고 있었어요!
I was saying for the love of god,
please don't rip off the tape!
모두 괜찮으세요?
다들 괜찮으신 거죠?
You guys okay?
Is everyone all right?
해냈군, 프리시오사
You did it, preciosa.
- 안녕하시오
- 디셔입니다
- Hey.
- Disher.
과일 맛 껌 한 통 주세요
Give me a pack of Juicy Fruit.
3층에서 총성이 울렸답니다
Shots fired, third floor.
세상에!
Oh, god!
3층에 응급반을 보내 주세요
Give me paramedics on three.
북쪽 별관입니다
요원 두 명이 쓰러져 있습니다
We're in the north wing.
We have two agents down.
생명엔 이상 없을 겁니다
두 사람 다 방탄조끼를 입고 있어요
They are gonna be okay.
They were both wearing vests.
위층으로 올라갔어요
They went up.
왜 위층으로 올라갔을까요?
Why would they go upstairs?
전화 좀 빌려 주실래요?
Can I use that phone?
이쪽으론 오지 않았어
Well, he didn't come through here.
지하실을 살펴봐
지하실에 사람을 내려보내
Get somebody in the basement.
- 주차장도 출입 통제하고
- 디셔입니다
- Lock down the parking garage.
- Disher.
경감님! 경감님!
몽크 선배입니다
Captain! Captain!
It's Monk.
몽크? / 이쪽입니다
천천히, 침착하게 가세요
Monk? / Right here, this way.
Slowly. Calm.
밖이야
Outside.
비켜요, 조심하세요!
Look out, look out!
안녕한가, 미겔!
Hello, Miguel!
당신이 바로 약혼자이신 모양이군
And you must be the fiancee.
당신은 위층에 있어야 하지 않나요?
Aren't you supposed to be upstairs?
어떤 사람들은 배심 의무를 피하려고
별짓을 다 하잖아요
Some people would do anything
to get out of jury duty.
내려오시죠
Step down, please.
어서
Come on.
이분은 6번이에요
This is number 6.
말수는 별로 없었지만
아주 중요한 역할을 했죠
She didn't say much, but she was
a very important part of the team.
- 잘 지내세요
- 네, 그럴게요
- Stay cool.
- I will. I'll stay cool. Yeah.
이제 팀의 일원이 됐군요?
정말 잘됐어요 / 네
Part of the team, huh?
Good for you. / Yeah.
- 이쪽은 2번이에요, 나탈리
- 안녕하세요
- And this is number 2. Natalie.
- Hello.
이분 말씀을 경청하세요
미국에 도움이 되는 분이세요
You should listen to this man.
He is good for America.
이쪽은 7번이에요
And this is number 7.
우리 둘이 공동 반장이었죠
뭐, 말하자면...
We were kinda co-captains, really.
I mean, sort of.
그리고... 저 사람은 4번이에요
I think and...
That's number 4.
처음에는 내 직감을 정말 싫어했지만
이젠 인정할 거예요
He sorta hated my guts in the beginning.
You can admit it now.
친목회 때 다시 봅시다. 알았죠?
I'll see at the reunion, okay?
일 년 후 오늘, 베니하나 식당에서요
One year from today, Benihana's.
그럴 일은 없을 거요
You know, that's not gonna happen.
- 정리 좀 하고 갈까 봐요
- 안 돼요
- I think I'll stay and straighten up.
- No.
- 가셔야죠
- 네
- We're going.
- Yeah.
자막제작 - NSC 자막팀
(http://club.nate.com/tsm)